Hello.
In this next lecture, I'm going to go over how we can add another enemy character.
So let's say I want to add another enemy, although I want it to use different animations.
In order to do that.
Let's first head back to our skin tone blueprint.
And we need to organize a few things.
So under variables we can put our variables into categories.
I want you to select this movement direction, variable and under category.
Just call this do not edit.
And then I want you to drag the Is that Bible and drag it under the do not edit.
Do the same with the enemy health bar.
And with the attack mode.
And with the attack event.
And do the same with the max health.
And the enemy damaged.
Okay, that should leave us with three variables to edit.
Wait time Max Warp speed and health.
I want us to go over to the jump nodes and just right click on this jump name and promote it to our
rival and cool this damaged jump mode.
Just compile this and make sure it is damaged or whatever it's called.
Then I want you to go to the second jump node, right click and promote it.
Terrible.
And call this death.
Trump made.
Then finally, I want you to go over to the attack template and just right click and promote the terrible
and call this attack jump node.
Ben, I'm willing to put all these rebels in a category called edit, so pull this edit and then I'll
move all the other variables to this category.
Once you've done this, just go compile and say.
And then right click on this content beep and look for create chart Blueprint class.
And we can just call this mini enemy underscore to.
And we just double click and hand side here.
There are only a couple of things I need to change in order to get this working with a different Sprite
as this melee enemy underscore, two is going to inherit all the blueprints of our original scan.
The first thing we need to change is the sprite survive a different sprite or just change it.
And then we need to go to animation component and change this to be the animation blueprint of the character.
Then if we just let army the enemy too, we don't need to edit anything in the do not edit section.
However, in the edit section we can change the wait time.
So this is how long our enemy will wait.
When it hits a wall or an edge, we can change it, speed its health.
And the reason we promoted this damage jump node death, jump node and attach upload is because if we
make another animation blueprint for a different 2D character, instead of jumping to whatever we call
it in the Scantron, you may name it something differently.
So here is where you can replace it and type it with something.
If you named it something differently, if you named it exactly the same in your other character, you
wouldn't need to change the variables here.
But just in case you do.
That's why we promoted this to a variable.
We can do the exact same thing for our ranged enemy, so let's set it up so that it can be easily cloned
and we can make more copies of it.
So if I just close this, go to my mushroom blueprint folder, open it up.
And if we just go over here to the Widget blueprint and under category, let's create a new category
and call it Do not edit.
We can move the enemy damage to the edit section, then we can just select health.
And we can put this in the category of edit.
And just move max health to edit and just move.
Is that to do not edit?
Then we go over to the jump nodes inside of our range enemy.
Sort of right click on this, promote it to a variable and call it ranged attack.
We can right click on this, promote it to rebel and call that.
Damaged.
We can right click on this, promote it to a Bible and call it death.
And then if you want to make your enemy use a different projectile, we can just right click on this.
Permit it to travel and call it projectile.
And just move all of these variables to the edit section.
And now you'd easily be able to create a chart blueprint Class of the Mushroom and create more ranged
characters.